Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajput.
I am an MBA in Finance and the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I have been working
in the corporate sector for 14 years.
Today I am presenting to you that on
19th July 2024, ICICI Prudential Life
Insurance has launched a new product called
Protect and Gain Growth.
Earlier also the company had this Protect and
Gain plan but that was a life option where
you
got a big insurance cover like term insurance and you
also got returns but this time along with the life option
they have brought a growth
option where you will get insurance cover up to 40 times your
annual premium
and along with that you will also get tax free
returns and exposure to equity.
Let's understand this plan
in details. If you like the video, then
I am presenting a little news article to you for your understanding.
If you look at the last seven months, the
stock market Sensex has come between 70000 to 80000 in the within seven
months and
people's expectations  It is believed that
by December 2025 next year, the Sensex share market will reach 1
lakh points. So, this is a positivity. Firstly, the
government is continuously stable. The
BJP government has been in power for the last three terms. It is a stable
government. Due to this, you are seeing
stability in the market and
good growth is visible. So, you
can take advantage of this by taking this policy. Now, look at the
returns the market has given over a period of
times in the last 25 years, from 1999 to
2004. In these 25 years, how did
your money double, triple, quadruple or
quintuple? Let us see in what percentage time. For example, the
number of years is written here,
5, 6, 7, 8, 15 years are written. And
here, how many times has your money doubled, tripled, four
or five times? Here,
you will see that if you look at the seven years, it is
79 times, that is, approximately 80
times. Your money has doubled within 7 years. In
this way, you have got returns
25 times within 7 years.
Money has tripled 15 times your
money quadrupled in just 7 years and
on 8 such a time has come when the stock market,
equity, Nifty 50 has multiplied your money
five times in 7 years, that is,
if you have invested 1 lakh, then
in 7 years it has become 5 lakh directly, but
your money has doubled about 80 times.
If you look at the three times returns,
how much money has tripled,
on 85 times your money has tripled within 11 years, your money has
quadrupled in 81 times.
If you look at it, in 13 years your
money has quadrupled, on
Nifty 15 and if you look at the five times
investment, it is at 87, in 15 years your
money has multiplied 5 times, so this is the power of
equity, power of here
you see the returns of investment, so the
longer you stay, the more
chances you have that the money is doubling,
triple or five times in a very quick
time, so the current market is
going on.  Those people in India who are saying
that it will cross 1 lakh in a short time,
then there is a very good opportunity for you too
where you can earn good money, you can
double or triple your money.
Eligibility Criteria of Protect
and Gain Growth Plan, Protect and Gain
Live Come, already
three videos are available on my YouTube, you
can watch them, this is the second option Growth
Option. Talking about its eligibility,
here you can take this policy with a minimum premium of 5 lakhs,
you cannot take this policy with a premium less than this, the
minimum premium should be 5 lakhs, the premium payment term is from 5 years to
12 years,
but this will also depend on your age, your premium payment
term, that how much
is your premium, your PPT will come accordingly,
you can select any policy term between 30 years to 40 years,
entry age is 18 years to 50 years, a
person can purchase this policy,
minimum insurance cover in this is 50 lakhs  The
maximum cover will be up to Rs 1 crore.
You
can also avail insurance cover of more than Rs 1 crore under the Protect and Gain option.
Individuals over 50 years of age can also
purchase this policy. There are several premium payment term
options, and premiums less than Rs 5 lakh can
also be paid. However,
these options have been designed keeping growth in mind.
This is the eligibility
criteria for this product.
In this plan, you will get
natural cover, accidental cover, and disability cover worth up to 40 times the premium under Protect and Gain.
Premium payment will be between 5 and 12 years. There will be
no medical test in this policy until the age of 45. If you are 45 and above, then a
video medical test and a physical medical test can
also be conducted. Along with this,
you will get insurance cover as per your declared income.
In this plan, you will get returns
and insurance cover like a ULIP.
However, to avail this plan, you must be at least
12th pass and have a minimum income of Rs 3 lakh.  It
is mandatory. You will get comprehensive protection
cover. I told you that you can take
natural cover, accidental cover and
disability cover up to 40 times. Along with this, you will get
income tax benefit.
You will get tax benefit under Section ATC of Income Tax
and you will get tax free income under Section 10 10D of Income Tax.
If
your premium is Rs 25 lakh or less, we
hope tomorrow is 23rd July. On 23rd July,
if the Finance Minister comes up with something new and
increases the ATC limit, then
you will definitely get the benefit of that too.
In this plan, you will not only get life cover but also maturity. On
maturity, you will get the fund value.
Switching option is also given in this policy
that if you want to switch from one fund to another,
you
can do it. Along with that, partial
withdrawal option is also given.
If you want to withdraw money after 5 years,
you can also do partial withdrawal. In this plan,
you will also get refunded the charges,
suppose premium allocation charges, whatever  The amount
deducted from your account will be refunded to you 100% from the 11th year onwards
and the mortality charges
deducted will be refunded 100% from the 11th year onwards and from the
26th year onwards you will be refunded Rs. 250. There will be a deduction
in your fund value. Along with this,
you will also get a maturity booster of Rs.
20, that is, the average of the fund value of the last nine years of the policy.
You will also get a maturity booster of Rs. 20. If you
invest in mutual funds etc.,
suppose your corpus there reaches Rs. 1
crore, then there is
no such facility available there, but here if the
corpus is Rs. 1 crore, then you will get Rs. 20 lakh as a
maturity booster.
Benefit illustration of ICICI Pro Protect and Gain Growth Plan.
Here, the customer whose age is 30 years, his name is
Anil Rajpat, is purchasing this policy
where he will pay premium for 12 years.
His premium is coming to Rs. 2438,
suppose in July 2024.  If they purchase the policy, the
policy will mature in July 2049. If
they get returns here, they will get a
tax-free income of Rs 1 crore 53,11723. Here,
from day one, there will be a life insurance cover of Rs 89
lakh, natural cover of Rs 89 lakh, accidental
cover of Rs 89 lakh, disability cover of Rs 89 lakh. Here,
you will get a rider premium of around Rs 10 lakh
with GST. The base premium will be
Rs 10 lakh.
In normal terms,
you get an insurance of Rs 25 lakh for Rs 1 lakh,
but here, there is an insurance cover of Rs 89 lakh,
plus accidental cover and
disability cover.
Talking about ICICI, till now they have covered the lives of around 10 crore
life insured people.
And from here, we understand that the product is
ICICI Pru Protect and Gain and the
option selected is the growth
option. The name of the old plan is the
life option. And the fund selected here  The
money will go to the selected Mid Small Cap 400 Index Fund at 25%, to Multi Cap at
25%, to Mid Cap at
25% and to Blue Chip Fund at 25%.
Investment has been made here and along with that the
option of systematic withdrawal has also been made yes so that the
money will come to your account systematically.
I will also tell you how. This
policy term has been taken for 40 years and the
premium payment term has been taken for 12 years.
Here you can see different premiums for
base, accidental cover and
disability cover. Now let us understand
that the base premium of
22638 is going into your investment.
In this, the premium allocation charges of
1347 which have been deducted will start getting returned to you from the 11th year. The
mortality charges which have been deducted will also start getting returned to you from the 11th year.
Mortality
charges will start getting two and a half times from the 26th year. Along with this,
you will
also get a maturity booster which will be 20% of your fund value, which is the
average fund value of the last nine years.  If
its value remains at 20, you will
also get a maturity booster. Along with this,
you will
get maturity at the end which will be tax free
because your investment is up to ₹ lakh.
Now I am telling you another option,
SWP. Suppose you have decided
that when you turn 61, if you are
taking this policy at the age of 30, then
your fund value will keep coming
into your automatic account systematically at 10. So
here you will notice that when
you turn 61, you will get Rs.
127000, 838 in your account. Next
year, you will get Rs. 116744, then Rs. 1135000.
Now, since I have withdrawn here at 10,
due to this you will see it decreasing here
because the fund value is decreasing.
This benefit
illustration chart of the fund value is made at 8,
whereas I am withdrawing money from 10, due to this
it is appearing less. Actual Fund
Performance  It can be more than 8%
as you have seen the fund performance in ICICI Portal
and you get returns up to 15% also, so
here if you are
getting returns at 15 and are withdrawing at 10, then
it will be shown in increasing order also, plus here
and the amount will be shown in increasing order,
so you are getting this money every year and
in the end you will
also get tax free maturity of Rs 1 crore 53 lakh 11723
and if you have taken this money every year for 10 years then
it also becomes more than a crore,
so in this way you can also select the systematic option,
if you want to
take it first, I took it from 61%, you
want it from 50%, you can also take it, so
you can select the systematic withdrawal option at different times,
then the
money will keep coming directly into your account, the
fund performance of the URI plan
depends on this, how will the returns of your investment be,
for example, if we talk about Maximizer Fund, then
what is ICICI, in 2001 it  The fund was
launched in 2024 and since then, it has
got a tax-free return of 16.0%
with insurance cover. So, you can see here
how the average return of the last 23 years is
sitting at 16%. Similarly,
you can see how different funds were launched and what has been their performance.
16%, 15%, 16%. All these funds were
launched in 2001. If I talk about
debt funds instead of equity, and
if you want to see them, I will
present them to you as well. I will just show you a little about the
products that have been launched in the recent past, like for example, the
funds that were launched in the last four-five years,
like for example, the Value Insur
Fund that was launched in 2018 has a
return of 15.71%. The Focus Fund that was launched in 2019 has a
return of 13%. The fund that was launched in 2019 has a
return of 17%. It is a mid-cap fund.  It was
launched in September 2022,
about two years ago, it has returns of around 39-40 per cent. The
mid-cap index fund which was
launched in September 2025 has returns of 35 to 36 per cent.
Just in February 2024, a
fund was launched, its returns of 16.2 per cent are also
available here. These are all
equity funds. If you
want to see balance funds as well, you can see the returns of balance funds
here as well. On the safe side,
you can also see the returns of day funds which are
FD type, which are absolutely safe so that even if the
market goes down, your money does not
come down. Their returns are also there, for example,
Protector Fund has a return of 8 per cent. Okay, so in
this way, you can see here that it is 8.92 per cent
in Capital Guarantee Debt Fund. In this way,
you can switch to equity
there too. Finally, if you choose this plan, then
this is a good plan.
ICICI Potential Life Insurance
already has many types of ULIP plans.
Like Signature is available
Platinum, they recently launched
Protect and Gain already with them
where you get a big insurance cover
under the Like option and this time keeping growth in
mind they have given the
option of growth in Protect and Gain, so
here you are expected to make good returns, the
market is quite positive right now and
you will also get the benefit of it, you are also getting income tax
benefits, so if
you like this plan and if you want to purchase from me
then call me on 0940 3412, thank
you so much, Jai Hind